Pride, Anne, 1942-1990. Papers of NOW officers, 1975-1979: A Finding Aid
Papers of NOW officers, 1975-1979
MC 484
Schlesinger Library, Radcliffe Institute
Anne Pride, 1942-1990
2 1/2 file boxes, 1 photograph folder
Papers of National Organization for Women board member and Do It NOW publications committee chair Anne Pride.
Accession numbers: 79-M279, 79-M294
These papers were given to the Schlesinger Library by Anne Pride in December 1979.
TERMS OF USE
Access. Unrestricted except that access to folders #1.1-3.13 is governed by a legal agreement between NOW and the Schlesinger Library and requires the written permission of NOW.
BIOGRAPHY
Anne Pride, National Organization for Women (NOW) activist and publisher, was born July 29, 1942, in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. She was appointed president of the feminist publishing company KNOW, Inc. (1969), and was on the board of directors of the Committee of Small Magazines Editors and Publishers (1974-1976). She served as editor of Do It NOW, NOW's national newsletter, and later served as chair of the Do It NOW publications committee. From 1975-1978, she served on the NOW Board of Directors. AP was also active in the Pittsburgh Action Against Rape, and the National Women's Political Caucus. She died April 24, 1990.
SCOPE AND CONTENT
This collection contains correspondence, printed material, budgets, mailing and subscription materials, and a photograph. The papers are arranged into three series and are arranged chronologically within the series.
Series I, Do It NOW (#1.1-2.9), contains correspondence dealing with subscriptions, advertisements, and criticisms of the newsletter. There are also budgets and mailing permit forms that contain circulation information, and a few advertisements that ran in the newsletter. Do It NOW became the National NOW Times in December 1979.
Series II, NOW Board of Directors (#2.10-3.13), contains correspondence relating to various issues facing the board, but the bulk is concerned with the controversy over the distribution of power in NOW. In addition to correspondence, there are printed materials from the Public Relations Committee and the Majority Caucus of NOW, a group of NOW members who in 1975 advocated a reorganization of NOW and a focusing of attention on issues such as lesbian rights, abortion, and rape.
Series III, Photograph (#3.14), contains one undated photograph of an anti-abortion protestor.
Folder headings are those of AP unless otherwise noted; archivist's headings and notes are in square brackets. All printed material by or about AP, as well as all printed material with annotations, has been kept in the collection. Other NOW publications and reports, except those created by AP, were transferred to the NOW records in the Schlesinger Library. Non-NOW printed material produced by mainstream organizations and publications was discarded; leaflets and other ephemera of small, transient organizations were retained.
INVENTORY
- Series I. DO IT NOW
  - [Do It NOW] advertising, prospects contacted, 1975-1976, 1.1.
  - Do It NOW subscriptions, 1975-1976, 1.2.
  - [Do It NOW] correspondence/sales, 1975-1977, 1.3.
  - [Do It NOW requests for information], 1975-1977, 1.4.
  - Do It NOW,1976, 1.5.
  - [Do It NOW] advertising [correspondence, rate information, samples, etc.], 1976, 1.6.
  - [Do It NOW] artists, 1976, 1.7.
  - [Do It NOW] correspondence with Pate Anderson, 1976, 1.8.
  - [Do It NOW] correspondence with Esther Kaw, 1976, 1.9.
  - [Do It NOW correspondence] with office staff, 1976, 1.10.
  - [Do It NOW correspondence re:] specific issues, 1976, 1.11.
  - [Do It NOW] postal correspondence, 1976, 1.12.
  - [Do It NOW] monthly [postal] forms, 1976-1977, 1.13.
  - [Do It NOW] Publications Committee correspondence, 1976, 1.14.
  - [Do It NOW] publication committee reports, 1976, 1.15.
  - [Do It NOW],1976-1977, 1.16.
  - [Do It NOW] advertising leads, 1976-1977, 1.17.
  - [Do It NOW] correspondence, 1976-1977, 2.1-2.2.
  - [Do It NOW advertisement] invoices paid, 1976-1977, 2.3.
  - [Do It NOW] requests for sales kits, 1976-1977, 2.4.
  - [Do It NOW] writers, 1976-1977, 2.5.
  - [Do It NOW advertisements], September 1977, 2.6.
  - [Do It NOW] photographers, 1977, 2.7.
  - National NOW Times advertisements, 1977-1978, 2.8-2.9.
- Series II. NOW BOARD OF DIRECTORS
  - Majority Caucus, 1974-1975, 2.10.
  - [NOW National Board] Alice Doesn't [strike], 1975, 2.11.
  - [NOW National] correspondence, 1975-1976, 2.12.
  - [NOW National Board meeting] Kansas City,July 1975, 3.1.
  - [NOW National] Board meeting, Philadelphia,October 1975, 3.2.
  - [NOW National] Board meeting, San Diego,December 1975, 3.3.
  - [NOW National] Board meeting, Phoenix, January 1976, 3.4.
  - [NOW National] Board meeting, Washington, D.C., April 1976, 3.5.
  - [NOW National] Board meeting, Cleveland,1976 June, 3.6.
  - [NOW National] Board meeting, Minneapolis, August 1976, 3.7.
  - [NOW] National Board meeting, Kansas City, October 1976, 3.8.
  - [NOW] National Conference, Detroit,1977, 3.9.
  - [NOW National] Board organization, 1976, 3.10.
  - NOW [National, AP] expenses, 1976, 3.11.
  - [NOW] memos and reports to the National Board, 1976, 3.12.
  - [NOW] Public Relations Committee [memos, AP member], 1976, 3.13.
- Series III. PHOTOGRAPH
  - Photograph of anti-abortion protestor, n.d., 3.14.
    FILED IN PHOTOGRAPH DRAWER.
Additional catalog entries
The following catalog entries represent persons, organizations, and topics documented in this collection. An entry for each appears in the Harvard On Line Library Information System (HOLLIS) and other automated bibliographic databases. THIS IS NOT AN INDEX.
Authors
Anderson, Pate; Kaw, Esther; National Organization for Women
Subjects
Do It NOW (Chicago, Ill.); Feminism--United States; Feminists--United States; National Organization for Women--Employees; National Organization for Women--Periodicals; NOW Majority Caucus; Sex discrimination against women--United States; Women--Legal status, laws, etc.--United States; Women's rights--United States